

# Supartiningsih

IT and Network Engineer

Surabaya City, Indonesia

I am Nining. I have been working since 2001 in the IT support and network operations field. I have experience with several Cisco, Juniper and Mikrotik network devices.

I can work well together with the whole team and manage it efficiently. I am also an independent individual, leading to self-motivational work.

I am available anytime and always online. I am ready to be relocated and willing to be placed anywhere.

in email: <a href="mailto:nining.networkengineer@gmail.com">nining.networkengineer@gmail.com</a> whatsapp: +62811530053

### Technical Skills

- Routing, Switching, TCP/IP, LAN, WAN
- VolP & PBX Systems
- FTTX Network, Broadband Technology
- Windows Server

- MySQL
- PHP, HTML, CSS
- Python
- **Graphic Design**

### **Work Experience**

### Network Delivery Engineer • PT NAP Info Lintas Nusa (Matrix) • Full Time

June 2021 - Present

- · Responsible for installing, maintaining and administrating fiber optic cable, configuring network devices and delivering internet services to clients. Having good knowledge of the FTTH concept.
- Mapping of the homepass and DPFO coverage using Google earth and other map apps.
- · Conduct network quality and doing PoC (proof of concept) tests before launching an internet product onto the market.

#### Independent Consultant • PT Oriflame Indonesia • Freelancer

September 2016 - June 2021



- Leading direct sales teams of cosmetic and personal care product companies through online marketing. Creating an interactive landing page website as a marketing tool for the team.
- Leading more than 100 people in the direct sales group and making online marketing strategies to achieve the group marketing target of at least 70 million rupiah every month.
- Achieve a minimum sales target of 140 million per month for two years and become the #12 Top Leader of Balikpapan in 2019 and 2020.

#### Data Communication Core Network Engineer • PT Telkomsel • Full Time

October 2010 - February 2015

- Responsible for administrating, configuring and troubleshooting Cisco network devices.
- Administrating firewall access for employees and third parties on CheckPoint devices.
- Internal complaint handling using a remedy ticketing system to solve problems according to SLA targets.



#### IT Regional Operation Engineer • PT Telkomsel • Full Time

September 2001 - October 2010



- Responsible for administrating, maintaining and troubleshooting all infrastructure devices in the regional office. Including network devices, PABX and local servers.
- Planning the concept of LAN, WAN, Wireless Access Point, VolP and extension telephone line (PBX) in the region office area.
- Application support troubleshooting for internal departments (sales, HRIS, finance)
- Responsible for troubleshooting computer software and hardware problems.
- Administrating regional Active Directory servers (Novell Netware).
- Creating local web tools for finance, HR & General Affairs.
- Setting and configuring PABX and creating web-based tools for generating password and extension numbers.
- Internal complaint handling using a remedy ticketing system to solve problems according to SLA targets.

### Internet Helpdesk • PT IndosatM2 • Apprenticeship

July 2001 - September 2001





2008 - 2017

1998 - 2001

### **Education**



### STMIK STIKOM Balikpapan

### **Bachelors Degree**

Majoring in Information Technology, Computer Science



### SMK Telkom Malang (Telkom School)

#### Senior High School

Majoring in Electronics & Informatics

### Course & Certificate

Leadership

Soft Skills

- Direct selling skill
- Digital marketing
- Video editing

### Languages

- Indonesian Native
- English

- CCNA 200 301 course *by IDN.id*
- Cisco Internetwork Troubleshooting (CIT) by Cisco, Certificate Number: 6205022333
- Interconnecting Cisco Network Devices (ICND) by Cisco, Certificate Number: 6205022045
- Unix System Administration by Sisindokom
- Introduction to Oracle8i: SQL and PL/SQL by Oracle
- HTML & CSS Fundamental Course by Progate
- Information Security Management System ISO 17799 & ISO 27001 Implementer by ERESHA

## Powered by CakeResume